<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kyle Lanchman&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>A blog by a tech nerd about random things. When I say &quot;random things,&quot; I probably mean tech things.</description>
    <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://kylelanchman.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 23:40:29 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 23:40:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Apple Hate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s amazing how much hate Apple gets when they release a new product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are complaining about the new MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I get that, but some people might be into that. I like the idea of having an ultra-portable laptop that I just do everything wirelessly on. Are we really able to do that yet? No, not really. But soon. Apple might be ahead of the curve with this one. Remember when they stopped putting optical drives in their computers? I thought it was silly then, but now I haven’t needed an optical disc for a long time…
I’m not saying I want one of these new MacBooks. I don’t. But it’ll be interesting to see what happens a couple years down the road with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are complaining about the Apple Watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Too expensive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What’s the point?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“{Pebble, Pebble Time, Android Wear, Galaxy Gear, Microsoft Band, whatever else} is better and cheaper.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a Pebble smartwatch user. I like it; it’s a good watch. It’s awesome to have notifications on my wrist, since I can never feel my phone vibrate in my pocket for some reason. It’s missing features that I’d like to have, though. Android Wear can do what I want, but I can’t use Android Wear with my iPhone. The new Pebble Time can do a lot of what I want, but it still has missing features. The Microsoft Band can’t do what I want on my iPhone.
The Apple Watch can do what I want, and I feel the Sport edition’s pricing is reasonable. (Pebble Time Steel will be $300, and the Apple Watch Sport 42mm is $400…not a very big difference, especially since the Pebble Time can’t do everything I’d like.)
You can’t compare all these watches to one another across platforms. They aren’t the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not so much that I’m a butthurt Apple fanboy as I am annoyed at all the inaccurate/unfair comparisons and just flat out misinformation that is going around right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the new MacBook is concerned: Give it time and see what happens. You might be surprised. You might even have something like it in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the Apple Watch is concerned: For now, this is the one watch for iPhones with deep integration like you get with Android Wear on Android devices. Third parties can try, but the experience won’t be anything like what Apple can offer, just like Android Wear offers a better experience than Pebble on Android (in my experience).
Moreover, wearable technology is something that still isn’t mainstream. Apple has a shot to &lt;em&gt;make&lt;/em&gt; it mainstream with this watch, which could even generate interest in all the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; smartwatches available now. Apple is just another competitor entering a quickly growing field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I still haven’t convinced you that Apple’s products and the products you like can coexist, I’ll leave you with this final thought: By constantly talking about Apple’s products, whether positively or negatively, you’re just giving them more advertisement, and probably more sales.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 15:03:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/03/11/apple-hate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/03/11/apple-hate.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackintosh Home Server: Part 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I left this off where I had a server with no OS, and a backup that was totally useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided trying to get the backup working was not worth my time, so I soldiered onwards trying to install Yosemite on the server. As luck would have it, the same distro I used for Mavericks now had a Yosemite version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took its good ol’ time, but the installer eventually booted. I was able to get Yosemite installed, and I was even able to use the Clover bootloader with this installation. Hopefully any system updates later on will be able to done easily with Clover…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to remove a couple of kexts that were causing some bad behavior, and I had to add a kext for my ethernet adapter, but that was about all. The only other odd behavior was that the installer didn’t seem to like my NVIDIA graphics card. I remedied this issue by simply using the onboard video during installation. Oddly, the NVIDIA card worked after installation…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackintosh computers are weird.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 17:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/02/15/hackintosh-home-server-pt4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/02/15/hackintosh-home-server-pt4.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackintosh Home Server: Part 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mentioned a few months ago that I was hoping the home server would be able to be upgraded to Yosemite when the time came. Over my winter break, I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now, the server was happily (albeit slowly) running using an OS X distro. Max resolution with the integrated Intel HD 3000 Graphics was 1280x1024, since OS X never supported HD 3000. Doing anything on screen or with screen sharing was insanely slow, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I happened to add an NVIDIA ION graphics card to my pile of decommissioned computer parts recently, so I decided I’d toss it into the server and see what happened. To my surprise, without any extra intervention, it worked! It was still a little slow, but it was running at 1920x1080 and screen sharing wasn’t abysmal anymore. Neat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was still on Mavericks, and every other Mac in the house was running Yosemite. That just won’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was not using Clover as my bootloader, so a straight upgrade to Yosemite was not really in the cards. I decided I’d do a Time Machine backup of the server, wipe it, and do a fresh install of Yosemite with Clover. Of course, that didn’t go as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up my OS X installer USB following &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tonymacx86.com/yosemite-desktop-guides/144426-how-install-os-x-yosemite-using-clover.html&quot;&gt;this forum post&lt;/a&gt;. It booted, but it would hang before actually getting to the installer. I tried the Unibeast method instead, which had never worked before. Rest assured that it still didn’t work. I didn’t expect it to, so I wasn’t let down or anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I didn’t want to put any more time into the thing, and I’d just restore my Time Machine backup I so cleverly made. So I popped in my old installer for the working distro and booted it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason Time Machine Restore was not an option, unlike on every other OS X installer I’ve used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There I was. I had a useless backup, and a server without an operating system…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 06:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/01/16/hackintosh-home-server-pt3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2015/01/16/hackintosh-home-server-pt3.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rant: Mobile Payments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time for a rant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been seeing a lot about an upcoming app called CurrentC, developed by a conglomerate of retailers including Wal-Mart and Best Buy, among many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is they want to make their own mobile payment system (à la Google Wallet or Apple Pay). They even want to offer discounts through the app. Sounds OK, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Well…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, you can only link a bank account to it. Presumably, this is so these retailers can avoid the fees they incur associated with credit cards. But, this hurts consumers because we’d be liable for fraudulent charges. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, but it needs my social security number and drivers license number, in addition to my bank account? And this information is all stored on their servers somewhere, not on my phone? I’m trusting this sensitive information to the same people who can’t keep my credit card number safe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare that with Apple Pay (I think Google Wallet works similarly). My credit card number is only stored in a secure hardware element on my device. When I pay for something, a one-time token is transmitted to authorize the payment, not my credit card number. Plus, I still have the protections my credit card offers me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This CurrentC had better be dead on arrival. And yet, I feel like when people see they can get 5% off their whole order at Wal-Mart, they’ll use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Stores like Rite Aid and CVS have begun blocking NFC payments (Apple Pay and Google Wallet) because they will only be accepting CurrentC when it comes out…&lt;em&gt;next year&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 19:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/10/27/rant-mobile-payments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/10/27/rant-mobile-payments.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackintosh Home Server, Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(Oh wow, it’s already been nearly a month since my last post? So I’ve been busy. Sue me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we know from last time, I came to the conclusion that running OS X on the server was my only real option for what I wanted to do, but I didn’t want to get new hardware. Usually if you want to run OS X on non-Apple hardware, you have to carefully pick components that will work &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; right with OS X. I didn’t have OS X in mind when I picked out the components for this server, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I figured I’d give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed a distro of OS X and proceeded to install it on the server. Imagine my surprise when it actually booted up! I was floored to say the least. However, being me, I managed to destroy it in less than an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reinstalled and promptly made a Time Machine backup &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; I ran any updates. This time everything went without (much of) a hitch! Everything I needed working seemed to be fine. The biggest issue was that I was stuck at a resolution of 1280x1024 and didn’t have any graphics acceleration, since the version of Intel integrated graphics I have isn’t supported by OS X. Whatever. It just makes it really laggy to use screen sharing, but it’s not a huge deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, by the end now, I have all sorts of goodies running on this thing. I have my typical array of things, like file sharing, a media server, a VPN server (which was amazingly easy to configure), and centralized backup (using Time Machine for the Macs and Crashplan for everything else!). However, I also got an easy-to-use web server, Git repository hosting, and other fun stuff! I’m loving it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just hope upgrading to Yosemite will be doable when the time comes…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 18:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/10/12/hackintosh-home-server-pt2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/10/12/hackintosh-home-server-pt2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hackintosh Home Server, Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Windows 8 on the server for a while now. It worked fine for what we needed. I didn’t care for the setup much, but I didn’t need to mess with it much either, so I got along fine with it overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But then I tried to host a website on it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed XAMPP for Windows and got to work migrating my website over. That wasn’t really an issue. However, the way I generate blog posts for Jekyll involves running a simple script that I wrote that moves some files around and invokes &lt;code&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt;, a Ruby gem…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Ruby and the Jekyll gem installed on the server was OK, but it’s easier on OS X or Linux. Still, all I had to do now was get my script to work remotely, since I generally write my blog posts away from home. Unfortunately, I never got this to work due to permissions issues related to how Cygwin &amp;amp; OpenSSH authenticated with public key auth on Windows. Back to the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I weighed my options. I needed iTunes for Home Sharing, some kind of web server, some kind of file sharing that works with OS X and Windows, an easy-to-configure VPN server, and a universal remote backup solution. Linux could do everything except iTunes, and Windows was out, which left me with OS X…except I wasn’t about to replace my server hardware with a brand new computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There was only one thing left to do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 06:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/09/16/hackintosh-home-server-pt1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/09/16/hackintosh-home-server-pt1.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Doing More With My Domain: Blogging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I promised myself I wouldn’t say I put a &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/148/&quot;&gt;“blag” on my “wobsite”&lt;/a&gt;, and yet I just can’t resist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased this domain name using &lt;a href=&quot;http://domains.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Domains&lt;/a&gt; (which is an awesome service, by the way! Get yourself a beta invite!). As soon as I got it, I redirected my GitHub Pages site to this domain. However, it didn’t feel like enough to just have my little one page site hosted here. I wanted to use my site for more than just general info and contact links. So…what about a blog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really see a clear way to host WordPress on GitHub Pages, and I felt like WordPress would be a bit overkill for what I wanted to do. GitHub Pages mentions something about Jekyll, so I looked into that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, the setup I have here may not be considered “typical.” I wanted to keep my main page largely as it was (a simple page made with Bootstrap), and I wanted to add a blog at /blog/. Beyond that, I wanted to maintain a similar theme across the website, so I needed to add Bootstrap to the blog. I actually found someone who had done something similar, so I followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.andrewmunsell.com/tutorials/jekyll-by-example/tutorial&quot;&gt;the guide on his website&lt;/a&gt; and tweaked things where I needed to. I’m pretty happy with the results!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I end up having time to update this blog semi-frequently. I have other stuff to talk about as far as how I’m using my domain to my advantage, and I always like to ramble on about tech stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 11:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/09/11/doing-more-with-my-domain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://kylelanchman.com/blog/2014/09/11/doing-more-with-my-domain.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
